<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>observed on Stuart Blackler's Blog</title><link>https://im5tu.io/categories/observed/</link><description>Recent content in observed on Stuart Blackler's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://im5tu.io/categories/observed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Observed No. 2 - Upgrade Your Terraform Modules</title><link>https://im5tu.io/article/2023/01/observed-no.-2-upgrade-your-terraform-modules/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://im5tu.io/article/2023/01/observed-no.-2-upgrade-your-terraform-modules/</guid><description>Welcome to the second edition of Observed! Your weekly newsletter, where I bring you a tip you can implement in your infrastructure across many categories like AWS, Terraform and General DevOps practices. This week&amp;rsquo;s edition looks at a technique you can use to upgrade your Terraform modules.
In case you aren’t sure what a Terraform module is, they are a self-contained package of Terraform configurations managed as a group. Modules can be used to create reusable components, improve organization and structure, and improve the reusability and maintainability of your infrastructure.</description></item><item><title>Observed No. 1 - VPC Endpoint Policies</title><link>https://im5tu.io/article/2023/01/observed-no.-1-vpc-endpoint-policies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://im5tu.io/article/2023/01/observed-no.-1-vpc-endpoint-policies/</guid><description>Welcome to the very first edition of Observed! Each week I bring you a tip you can implement in your infrastructure across many categories like AWS, Terraform and General DevOps practices. This week&amp;rsquo;s edition looks at VPC endpoint policies in AWS.
What Are VPC Endpoints? VPC endpoints are network interfaces you can create in your VPC to enable communication between your VPC and other AWS services without using an Internet gateway, VPN, or VPC peering.</description></item></channel></rss>