<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>devops on CodeWithStu's Blog</title><link>https://im5tu.io/tags/devops/</link><description>Recent content in devops on CodeWithStu's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 01:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://im5tu.io/tags/devops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Observed No. 12 - Removing Pre-Commit Dependencies With Docker</title><link>https://im5tu.io/article/2023/05/observed-no.-12-removing-pre-commit-dependencies-with-docker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://im5tu.io/article/2023/05/observed-no.-12-removing-pre-commit-dependencies-with-docker/</guid><description>Welcome to the 12th edition of Observed! The newsletter delivers a tip you can implement across many categories like AWS, Terraform and General DevOps practices in your infrastructure. This week&amp;rsquo;s edition looks how we can use Precommit with existing docker images.</description></item><item><title>Observed No. 11 - Saving Costs on AWS</title><link>https://im5tu.io/article/2023/04/observed-no.-11-saving-costs-on-aws/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://im5tu.io/article/2023/04/observed-no.-11-saving-costs-on-aws/</guid><description>Welcome to the 11th edition of Observed! The newsletter delivers a tip you can implement across many categories like AWS, Terraform and General DevOps practices in your infrastructure. This week&amp;rsquo;s edition looks at AWS Cost Savings.
Every company seems to be cutting costs in one way or another. Let’s look at different ways you can visualize and reduce costs.</description></item><item><title>Observed No. 10 - Chaos Engineering on AWS</title><link>https://im5tu.io/article/2023/03/observed-no.-10-chaos-engineering-on-aws/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://im5tu.io/article/2023/03/observed-no.-10-chaos-engineering-on-aws/</guid><description>Welcome to the 10th edition of Observed! Your weekly newsletter, where I bring you a tip you can implement in your infrastructure across many categories like AWS, Terraform and General DevOps practices. This week&amp;rsquo;s edition looks at the practice of Chaos Engineering.</description></item><item><title>Observed No. 9 - SLIs vs SLOs vs SLAs</title><link>https://im5tu.io/article/2023/03/observed-no.-9-slis-vs-slos-vs-slas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://im5tu.io/article/2023/03/observed-no.-9-slis-vs-slos-vs-slas/</guid><description>Welcome to the 9th edition of Observed! Your weekly newsletter, where I bring you a tip you can implement in your infrastructure across many categories like AWS, Terraform and General DevOps practices. This week&amp;rsquo;s edition examines the differences between SLIs, SLOs and SLAs.</description></item><item><title>Observed No. 8 - Continuous Integration vs Continuous Delivery vs Continuous Deployment</title><link>https://im5tu.io/article/2023/03/observed-no.-8-continuous-integration-vs-continuous-delivery-vs-continuous-deployment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://im5tu.io/article/2023/03/observed-no.-8-continuous-integration-vs-continuous-delivery-vs-continuous-deployment/</guid><description>Welcome to the 8th edition of Observed! Your weekly newsletter, where I bring you a tip you can implement in your infrastructure across many categories like AWS, Terraform and General DevOps practices. This week&amp;rsquo;s edition looks at the differences between continuous integration, continuous delivery and continuous deployment.</description></item><item><title>Observed No. 7 - Well Architected</title><link>https://im5tu.io/article/2023/02/observed-no.-7-well-architected/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://im5tu.io/article/2023/02/observed-no.-7-well-architected/</guid><description>Welcome to the seventh edition of Observed! Your weekly newsletter, where I bring you a tip you can implement in your infrastructure across many categories like AWS, Terraform and General DevOps practices. This week&amp;rsquo;s edition looks at the Well-Architected framework.</description></item><item><title>Unlocking the best of AWS Route 53</title><link>https://im5tu.io/video/unlocking-the-best-of-aws-route-53/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 07:47:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://im5tu.io/video/unlocking-the-best-of-aws-route-53/</guid><description>In this video, I will show you the power of wildcards, health checks, and, my favourite, a Netflix-style multi-region DNS setup for scenarios on AWS Route 53. You&amp;rsquo;ll learn about the many capabilities of this service and how to use it to your advantage. Each section is accompanied by Terraform code. This video was originally was posted under DevOpsWithStu, but since then I have merged the channels together.</description></item><item><title>How to Use AWS IAM Identity Centre with Terraform</title><link>https://im5tu.io/video/how-to-use-aws-iam-identity-centre-with-terraform/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 07:46:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://im5tu.io/video/how-to-use-aws-iam-identity-centre-with-terraform/</guid><description>This video will look at how to log in with AWS IAM Identity Centre and what to do when Terraform doesn&amp;rsquo;t work out of the box! Learn some of the inner mechanics behind AWS SSO Login. This video was originally was posted under DevOpsWithStu, but since then I have merged the channels together.</description></item><item><title>Create Terraform Modules Like A Pro</title><link>https://im5tu.io/video/create-terraform-modules-like-a-pro/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 07:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://im5tu.io/video/create-terraform-modules-like-a-pro/</guid><description>In this video, we&amp;rsquo;ll look at a technique you can use to upgrade your Terraform modules. Over the course of the last 4/5 years, I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed that there is always a trend within companies to build modules for specific things/use cases. Rarely do I see these teams account for the one thing they need to operate the infrastructure they make. This video was originally was posted under DevOpsWithStu, but since then I have merged the channels together.</description></item><item><title>Observed No. 6 - Service Meshes</title><link>https://im5tu.io/article/2023/02/observed-no.-6-service-meshes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://im5tu.io/article/2023/02/observed-no.-6-service-meshes/</guid><description>Welcome to the sixth edition of Observed! Your weekly newsletter, where I bring you a tip you can implement in your infrastructure across many categories like AWS, Terraform and General DevOps practices. This week&amp;rsquo;s edition looks at service meshes.
What is a service mesh? A service mesh is dedicated infrastructure for managing service-to-service communication within a microservices architecture. It provides a way to manage the complex network of microservices by adding a layer of abstraction between the services and the underlying network.</description></item><item><title>Observed No. 5 - MACH Architectures</title><link>https://im5tu.io/article/2023/01/observed-no.-5-mach-architectures/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://im5tu.io/article/2023/01/observed-no.-5-mach-architectures/</guid><description>Welcome to the fifth edition of Observed! Your weekly newsletter, where I bring you a tip you can implement in your infrastructure across many categories like AWS, Terraform and General DevOps practices. This week&amp;rsquo;s edition looks at MACH architectures.</description></item><item><title>Observed No. 4 - Emerging Pattern: Centralised Ingress</title><link>https://im5tu.io/article/2023/01/observed-no.-4-emerging-pattern-centralised-ingress/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://im5tu.io/article/2023/01/observed-no.-4-emerging-pattern-centralised-ingress/</guid><description>Welcome to the fourth edition of Observed! Your weekly newsletter, where I bring you a tip you can implement in your infrastructure across many categories like AWS, Terraform and General DevOps practices. This week&amp;rsquo;s edition looks at a common pattern emerging across the industry: Centralised Ingress.</description></item><item><title>Observed No. 3 - Understanding Split Horizon DNS: How it works and How to Implement it in AWS</title><link>https://im5tu.io/article/2023/01/observed-no.-3-understanding-split-horizon-dns-how-it-works-and-how-to-implement-it-in-aws/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://im5tu.io/article/2023/01/observed-no.-3-understanding-split-horizon-dns-how-it-works-and-how-to-implement-it-in-aws/</guid><description>Welcome to the third edition of Observed! Your weekly newsletter, where I bring you a tip you can implement in your infrastructure across many categories like AWS, Terraform and General DevOps practices. This week&amp;rsquo;s edition looks at Split Horizon DNS.</description></item><item><title>Observed No. 2 - Upgrade Your Terraform Modules</title><link>https://im5tu.io/article/2023/01/observed-no.-2-upgrade-your-terraform-modules/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://im5tu.io/article/2023/01/observed-no.-2-upgrade-your-terraform-modules/</guid><description>Welcome to the second edition of Observed! Your weekly newsletter, where I bring you a tip you can implement in your infrastructure across many categories like AWS, Terraform and General DevOps practices. This week&amp;rsquo;s edition looks at a technique you can use to upgrade your Terraform modules.</description></item><item><title>Observed No. 1 - VPC Endpoint Policies</title><link>https://im5tu.io/article/2023/01/observed-no.-1-vpc-endpoint-policies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://im5tu.io/article/2023/01/observed-no.-1-vpc-endpoint-policies/</guid><description>Welcome to the very first edition of Observed! Each week I bring you a tip you can implement in your infrastructure across many categories like AWS, Terraform and General DevOps practices. This week&amp;rsquo;s edition looks at VPC endpoint policies in AWS.
What Are VPC Endpoints? VPC endpoints are network interfaces you can create in your VPC to enable communication between your VPC and other AWS services without using an Internet gateway, VPN, or VPC peering.</description></item><item><title>Live: Serverless SaaS</title><link>https://im5tu.io/video/live-serverless-saas/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 09:44:15 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://im5tu.io/video/live-serverless-saas/</guid><description>In this session, I&amp;rsquo;m going to build out a design for a serverless SaaS solution on AWS. This takes into account things like budgetting and technology choices. The aim will be to to deploy a regionally independent solution.</description></item><item><title>Live AWS System Design: Payments Gateway</title><link>https://im5tu.io/video/live-aws-system-design-payments-gateway/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 10:08:30 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://im5tu.io/video/live-aws-system-design-payments-gateway/</guid><description>In this session, we are going to design a typically Payments Gateway that you would be expected to design as part of the hiring process for a FinTech. We will about some of the considerations to take into account when facing this question in a systems design interview.</description></item><item><title>Live: AWS Multi-Account Structure Design</title><link>https://im5tu.io/video/live-aws-multi-account-structure-design/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 09:20:59 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://im5tu.io/video/live-aws-multi-account-structure-design/</guid><description>In this session, we are going to design an AWS Multi-Account structure and the networking behind it. We will learn how to connect different accounts together and some of the considerations to take into account when facing this question in a systems design interview.</description></item><item><title>Live: Systems Design - Stock Tick API</title><link>https://im5tu.io/video/live-systems-design-stock-tick-api/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 09:36:49 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://im5tu.io/video/live-systems-design-stock-tick-api/</guid><description>In this session, we are going to design a fairly typical stock trading API. We are going to go through some of the considerations that you need to have as well as looking at some of the curve balls that you may face. This will help you design distributed systems and data intensive applications using an event driven architecture.</description></item><item><title>How to set up OpenTelemetry Collector on Kubernetes</title><link>https://im5tu.io/video/how-to-set-up-opentelemetry-collector-on-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 12:00:07 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://im5tu.io/video/how-to-set-up-opentelemetry-collector-on-kubernetes/</guid><description>OpenTelemetry loves Kubernetes, which is clear to see from the OpenTelemetry Operator for Kubernetes. In this video, you will learn:
How to install the OpenTelemetry Operator How to automatically inject a sidecar into a pod How to create a new collector configuration How to add automatic instrumentation for supported languages</description></item></channel></rss>