<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>opentelemetry on CodeWithStu's Blog</title><link>https://im5tu.io/tags/opentelemetry/</link><description>Recent content in opentelemetry on CodeWithStu's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 12:00:07 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://im5tu.io/tags/opentelemetry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to set up OpenTelemetry Collector on Kubernetes</title><link>https://im5tu.io/video/how-to-set-up-opentelemetry-collector-on-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 12:00:07 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://im5tu.io/video/how-to-set-up-opentelemetry-collector-on-kubernetes/</guid><description>&lt;p>OpenTelemetry loves Kubernetes, which is clear to see from the OpenTelemetry Operator for Kubernetes. In this video, you will learn:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>How to install the OpenTelemetry Operator&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How to automatically inject a sidecar into a pod&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How to create a new collector configuration&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How to add automatic instrumentation for supported languages&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Running an OpenTelemetry Collector locally with Docker</title><link>https://im5tu.io/video/running-an-opentelemetry-collector-locally-with-docker/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 17:00:15 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://im5tu.io/video/running-an-opentelemetry-collector-locally-with-docker/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recently we’ve looked into adding logs, metrics &amp;amp; traces using console exporters. In reality, we want to send this telemetry to one or more places. Collectors allow your service to offload data quickly, standardise access to protected exporter endpoints and can take care of additional handling like retries and batching.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this video, you will learn:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The difference between the standard collector and the contributors collector&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How to run an OpenTelemetry Collector using docker compose&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How to configure an OpenTelemetry Collector&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Metrics in .NET has never been easier - OpenTelemetry</title><link>https://im5tu.io/video/metrics-in-net-has-never-been-easier-opentelemetry/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 17:00:09 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://im5tu.io/video/metrics-in-net-has-never-been-easier-opentelemetry/</guid><description>&lt;p>Metrics are often handled via one of many protocols. The new contender to this is OpenTelemetry - a system for sending your logs, traces and metrics. This OpenTelemetry tutorial will guide you through how to setup a .NET Application to export your .NET metrics and do basic processing. You’re going to learn the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>How to edit and drop metrics&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How to setup application metrics with OpenTelemetry using the console exporter&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How to add external instrumentation like runtime metrics&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>How to Setup OpenTelemetry Logging in .NET</title><link>https://im5tu.io/video/how-to-setup-opentelemetry-logging-in-net/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 17:45:03 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://im5tu.io/video/how-to-setup-opentelemetry-logging-in-net/</guid><description>&lt;p>You’ve discovered that OpenTelemetry can send logs as well as traces but you’re not sure how set this up? This OpenTelemetry tutorial will guide you through how to setup a .NET Application to include log exports and do basic processing. All your logs and traces will be linked automatically.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>OpenTelemetry: Simple Distributed Tracing in .NET Libraries</title><link>https://im5tu.io/video/opentelemetry-simple-distributed-tracing-in-net-libraries/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 07:00:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://im5tu.io/video/opentelemetry-simple-distributed-tracing-in-net-libraries/</guid><description>&lt;p>Following on from our introductory video, this OpenTelemetry tutorial walks through how to add custom ActivitySources that can be used in many libraries such as OpenTelemetry to support a distributed tracing scenario, without creating any dependencies. This is incredibly powerful for .NET library authors as they don&amp;rsquo;t have to wait for .NET 5 to take advantage of this amazing capability.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Get Started With OpenTelemetry Tracing and ASP.NET Core</title><link>https://im5tu.io/video/get-started-with-opentelemetry-tracing-and-asp-net-core/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 14:00:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://im5tu.io/video/get-started-with-opentelemetry-tracing-and-asp-net-core/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this OpenTelemetry Tutorial, take a look at how to quickly get up and running with OpenTelemetry in an ASP.NET Core application. You&amp;rsquo;ll learn how to setup the automatic instrumentation for both inbound and outbound web requests and how to configure the Jaeger Exporter (&lt;a href="https://jaegertracing.io">https://jaegertracing.io&lt;/a>) - running it all in a local environment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For more information about the differences between OpenTelemetry and what is available in .NET out of the box, also checkout this article by Rehan Saeed: &lt;a href="https://rehansaeed.com/deep-dive-into-open-telemetry-for-net/">https://rehansaeed.com/deep-dive-into-open-telemetry-for-net/&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>