<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Things you might not know about CSharp on CodeWithStu's Blog</title><link>https://im5tu.io/series/things-you-might-not-know-about-csharp/</link><description>Recent content in Things you might not know about CSharp on CodeWithStu's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 08:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://im5tu.io/series/things-you-might-not-know-about-csharp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Things you might not know about CSharp - Duck Typing</title><link>https://im5tu.io/article/2022/01/things-you-might-not-know-about-csharp-duck-typing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://im5tu.io/article/2022/01/things-you-might-not-know-about-csharp-duck-typing/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is the next part of my series taking a look at some of the lesser known features of the C# language. Today we will be looking at duck typing and how it is used in C#. Much like the previous article, your millage may vary in terms of actually using these features for day to day programming, so think of this series as raising awareness that these things exist, not that you should use for general purpose programming. Without further adieu&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Things you might not know about CSharp - Using Params with Indexers</title><link>https://im5tu.io/article/2022/01/things-you-might-not-know-about-csharp-using-params-with-indexers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://im5tu.io/article/2022/01/things-you-might-not-know-about-csharp-using-params-with-indexers/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is the first part of my series taking a look at some of the lesser known features of the C# language. Today we will be looking at index parameters, specifically how to use &lt;code>params&lt;/code> with them, and how they are used in C#. With these articles, your millage may vary in terms of usability of these features for day to day programming, so think of this series as raising awareness that these things exist, not that you should use for general purpose programming. Without further adieu&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>