<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>January on CodeWithStu's Blog</title><link>https://im5tu.io/article/2023/01/</link><description>Recent content in January on CodeWithStu's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><atom:link href="https://im5tu.io/article/2023/01/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Observed No. 5 - MACH Architectures</title><link>https://im5tu.io/article/2023/01/observed-no.-5-mach-architectures/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://im5tu.io/article/2023/01/observed-no.-5-mach-architectures/</guid><description>Welcome to the fifth edition of Observed! Your weekly newsletter, where I bring you a tip you can implement in your infrastructure across many categories like AWS, Terraform and General DevOps practices. This week&amp;rsquo;s edition looks at MACH architectures.</description></item><item><title>Observed No. 4 - Emerging Pattern: Centralised Ingress</title><link>https://im5tu.io/article/2023/01/observed-no.-4-emerging-pattern-centralised-ingress/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://im5tu.io/article/2023/01/observed-no.-4-emerging-pattern-centralised-ingress/</guid><description>Welcome to the fourth edition of Observed! Your weekly newsletter, where I bring you a tip you can implement in your infrastructure across many categories like AWS, Terraform and General DevOps practices. This week&amp;rsquo;s edition looks at a common pattern emerging across the industry: Centralised Ingress.</description></item><item><title>Observed No. 3 - Understanding Split Horizon DNS: How it works and How to Implement it in AWS</title><link>https://im5tu.io/article/2023/01/observed-no.-3-understanding-split-horizon-dns-how-it-works-and-how-to-implement-it-in-aws/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://im5tu.io/article/2023/01/observed-no.-3-understanding-split-horizon-dns-how-it-works-and-how-to-implement-it-in-aws/</guid><description>Welcome to the third edition of Observed! Your weekly newsletter, where I bring you a tip you can implement in your infrastructure across many categories like AWS, Terraform and General DevOps practices. This week&amp;rsquo;s edition looks at Split Horizon DNS.</description></item><item><title>Observed No. 2 - Upgrade Your Terraform Modules</title><link>https://im5tu.io/article/2023/01/observed-no.-2-upgrade-your-terraform-modules/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://im5tu.io/article/2023/01/observed-no.-2-upgrade-your-terraform-modules/</guid><description>Welcome to the second edition of Observed! Your weekly newsletter, where I bring you a tip you can implement in your infrastructure across many categories like AWS, Terraform and General DevOps practices. This week&amp;rsquo;s edition looks at a technique you can use to upgrade your Terraform modules.</description></item><item><title>Observed No. 1 - VPC Endpoint Policies</title><link>https://im5tu.io/article/2023/01/observed-no.-1-vpc-endpoint-policies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://im5tu.io/article/2023/01/observed-no.-1-vpc-endpoint-policies/</guid><description>Welcome to the very first edition of Observed! Each week I bring you a tip you can implement in your infrastructure across many categories like AWS, Terraform and General DevOps practices. This week&amp;rsquo;s edition looks at VPC endpoint policies in AWS.
What Are VPC Endpoints? VPC endpoints are network interfaces you can create in your VPC to enable communication between your VPC and other AWS services without using an Internet gateway, VPN, or VPC peering.</description></item></channel></rss>